Welcome To FurTuner
In this video we will guide you through the steps to create a balanced diet for your pet
Select start to create beginning your pet's diet
Choose your pet type
Choose the type of diet
Enter your pets information
You can now begin selecting the food ingredients for your recipe
Some ingredients group are mandatory, showing blue while others are optional showing in orange
each group has a minimum and maximum number of ingredients that you can select
For example you must select at least one meat group ingredient from this group but you may select up to 3
the optional groups have a maximum number of ingredients that can be selected if you choose to
Scroll through and choose the rest of the ingredients for your recipe
The blue ingredients are the foods you selected for your recipe
Depending on your selection, FurTuner may also include some additional balancing ingredients from this orange list
These ingredients are used when needed to help ensure that the final diet is complete and balanced
This table displays the complete nutritional profile of the diet including total energy, protein percentage, fat percentage, essential amino acids, essential fatty acids, minerals and vitamins
Here under the status you will be able to see whether each nutrient meets or exceeds the minimum AAFCO requirements
If you are satisfied with your diet you can proceed to payment
Once payment has been completed your final recipe will be available to print or email to you
The recipe will contain the amounts of each ingredient in grams and you will have a recipe for one day and up to 30 days
Your printed report will also include the nutritional profile of the diet
The report will also include instructions for preparing THE DIET